Just recently,
SAP released the MCP Gateway in SAP
Integration Suite.
This new component allows the integration
of Copiled Studio with SAP in a fully
endorsed and compliant way.
When I look at current customer projects,
I can see many different architectures.
The new MCP Gateway in SAP Integration
Suite is one of two explicitly mentioned
architectures endorsed by SAP in the
SAPAPI policy.
In this video,
we will show how to set up the MCP
Gateway from scratch connected to an
external Odata service,
which actually means that the SAP API
policy does not even apply,
and connect it to Copal Studio using an
API management solution.
In our scenario,
we're using Azure API Management because
it gives us flexibility with
authentication and additional throttling.
In future videos,
we will also show other architectures
with less components and complexity and
show how this can be used to connect to
your SAP system.
Let's get started.
The first great thing is that SAP made
the MCP Gateway available on the SAP
Business Technology Platform trial
environment,
which means everyone can quickly give it
a try.
In my setup,
I have already provisioned a trial
instance on Azure,
and in these next steps,
I'll just set up the integration suite,
add the required capabilities,
assign roles to my user,
and enable the integration cell.
With all of that I'm ready to start the
actual configuration of the MCP Gateway.
Now in integration suite we can go to
design integrations and APIs and create a
so-called integration package.
This integration package will hold all
our artefacts.
So we'll give this integration package a
name like MCP test package,
technical name and also a short
description.
With this we can save the package and
then add certain artifacts to this
package.
In our case we will only add the MC
server.
As mentioned before,
we are going to connect to an external
API from here.
From the MCP server we could also connect
to existing APIs that are already proxied
by SAPAPI management.
In our our case we are connecting to an
external API and there's actually a nice
Star Wars API that allows you to fetch
information about planets and people from
from Star Wars.
So we are going to select this Swappy API.
We just provide the URL here we again
give it a name SWAPI.
We provide the MCP path.
This will be the path that will be
accessed later on by by our client and we
can click on.
OK, now we just have the basic connection.
But obviously the MCP server does not
know about the available tools.
It does not know about the resources.
So the next thing is that we provide more
details to the specific API.
So we click on edit,
go to edit API specification and we
upload and open API specifications for
the swap API.
This one is actually something that I
created.
You can also download it from the show
notes.
And just to get started,
now that the API has some meaning,
we have specified all the resources.
We can go to tools and actually select
the tools that we want to expose in the
SAPMMCP server.
So we select films, people, planets,
species and so on.
We leave out the schemas because
obviously that is not something that we
necessarily need to expose via the MCP
server.
Now we are good to go.
We can again go to the policies and here
you can actually see the out-of-the-box
configuration.
We could do some modifications here which
we will do in in later videos,
but for now we'll just use the default
steps in the policy,
which basically is the authentication
step which uses client,
either client certificates or auth.
And there's also an authorization step
which for example specifically looks for
a certain scope only.
If these two things are correct,
if there's the correct authentication and
the correct authorization,
then the users will be able to access
this MCP server.
Again,
we could do some modifications here,
but for now we just want to have the
out-of-the-box experience.
So we'll click on save and we also
trigger the deployment to the integration
suite.
So while the deployment is is running we
want to make sure that we have the right
access to call the MCP server.
The easiest way to to do give it a simple
try is to create a so-called service key
which gives us a client Ida client secret
which we then can use to call the MCP
server.
We could create this manually,
but actually if we are in our PTP cockpit,
we can use the booster functionality to
create the service keys for us.
So we'll go to the booster,
we'll look for the integration suite,
and here if we select the integration
suite,
the service keys can be created for us.
Now that we have a service key created,
we have to ensure that we actually have
the right scope in place.
So so the one that was also queried for
in our policy.
So we'll go to update here and in the
parameters tab,
we'll make sure that we have the right
scope API dot invoke mentioned here as
well.
With this,
the access token that we would create
using the client ID and client secret
from the service key should provide us
with all the relevant details to actually
call the MCP server.
So now that everything is configured,
let's take the client ID,
client service and we can actually test
our MCP server already using Visual
Studio Code.
So the MCP server is deployed,
which means if we switch over to Visual
Studio Code,
and this is just a very simple test,
obviously we could do the same thing with
the MCP inspector or we could go directly
to Copilot Studio or something like that.
But just to have a simple test,
we'll use Visual Studio Code to do some
HTTP calls.
So basically the first thing is we call
the token endpoint all the information
there with the client secret,
the the the client ID is there and we get
an access token back from the SAP system.
If you use a Jot decoder,
we can actually take a look at this
access token and we can see that the
scopes,
the authorities are actually defined as
what we had defined in the BTP cockpit
when we created the service keys.
So it looks like everything is OK.
We have a correct access token,
which means in our next call,
we can use this access token to actually
call the MCP endpoint.
So we, we have everything in place,
the scope is correct,
which means if we do the next step,
if we call now our MCP endpoint with a
correct payload, obviously,
and with the access token,
we should get a success message back from
the MCP gateway.
That's actually exactly what we're doing.
We can see the reply from the MCP server.
We can see that our Star Wars API,
the MCP server of the Star Wars API was
successful.
Now we can also do to a tool list to
actually see all the tools that have been
made available by the MCP gateway.
And again we make the call from Visual
Studio Code and we get all the different
tools back here in Visual Studio Code,
which means it looks like everything is
in place.
We have now a way to call our BTP service
to do the correct authentication to have
the right authorization,
and then we get the very same tools back
in Visual Studio Code in our client as we
would expect from BTP.
With all these preparations,
we are actually good to go to consume our
MCP gateway with the Star Wars API tools
in a real client.
So here we'll switch over to Cobalt
Studio.
In Cobalt Studio,
I've already created an agent,
which is basically an Mt agent.
And the first thing that we want to do is
add this MCP server as a tool to our
client.
So we'll give it a name,
the Star Wars API,
we'll give it a description,
which obviously is really important
because this description will tell Copal
Studio that this is the right MCP server
to call in case there is a Star Wars
related question.
So the remaining thing is our actual URL
to the MCP server.
Now,
since we just saw that we need to have a
certain kind of authentication in our
case,
we'll not connect to the MCP server on
BTP directly,
but we'll use an Azure API management and
as an intermediate proxy in Azure API
Management,
we do the very same authentication flow
as what we did in Visual Studio Code.
So we'll use a policy to connect to the
the token end point.
We'll fetch the access token,
we'll take the access token and then
forward this access token to the
appropriate MCP gateway.
So all of this is already done.
And again,
you can find all the details in the show
notes if in in case if you want to
replicate the scenario,
but we'll do we're,
we are actually doing the very same
things that we did in Blue Studio code.
Now in API management,
this means we have a different end point.
So this is our new MCP endpoint basically
that we'll use in Copile Studio.
We can also protect our API with an API
key.
And so with these two informations,
we'll go back to Copile Studio.
In Copal Studio,
we paste the URL to the Azure API machine,
which again will then call the MCP server.
On BTP,
we'll provide the header information X
Dash and API Dash key.
And we also provide then the actual API
key which allows us to call the API
service.
When we now click on add and configure,
Copal Studio will actually call the MCP
server.
So actually it's will call the Azure API
management.
Azure APMI management will do the
authentication,
will then call the MCP gateway on BTP.
And we can already see here the tools
that are fetched from the SAP system.
So with this we are ready to start here
in Copal Studio.
In our test environment,
we can just and ask a a question about
Star Wars.
So what can tell me about Episode 4?
Copal Studio now has a complete overview
of all the tools exposed from the MCP
server.
It finds the required tool that actually
returns the film information and it
returns this information here directly in
Copal Studio.
Now I can obviously interact with this
API or with this MCP server.
I can ask other questions,
I can combine different tools in here.
So now I have really the flexibility that
the MCP server provides me to connect to
this arbitrary API in the background
system.
Obviously from copilot studio I can also
deploy this to Teams.
I can also deploy this to copilot,
M365 copilot or to Excel or to Word or
PowerPoint or something like that.
So with this MCP protocol it's very easy
to get the the data into different
clients.
And in our case,
we just showed how to do this in in in
Copal Studio using the new MCP Gateway on
SAP Integration Suite.
I hope this video will help you to
quickly get started with the new MCP
Gateway on Integration Suite as set.
This is the first one.
We'll continue to explore additional
authentication and architecture options,
but I hope this this can really help you
to get started.
Thank you so much for watching.